RESUME SUMMARY

I am Priyadarshini Tamilselvan, a Full Stack Software Developer with over 5+ years of successful experience in web development and mobile application development. Recognised consistently for performance excellence and contributions to success infront-end development and UI/UX improvements. Strengths in backend development using Python while working in D.E. Shaw & Co, a Fintech company, and Android, Flutter with basic knowledge in Spring Boot and Hibernate backed by working in a startup.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

December 2022- June 2024 | Dealsplus, UK

SDE - II

- Working on Spring boot application for Private Equity Firm fund management.
- Led NP-hard problem resolution: Addressed the NP-hard problem of structuring complex ownership data through graphical representations.
- Optimised Cap Table Outputs: Spearheaded the development of efficient algorithms for generating precise and effective ownership outputs in the cap tables.
- Enhanced Front-End Testing: Implemented improvements to front-end test suites, elevating overall software quality and performance.

April 2021-November 2022 | Avinya

Co-Founder

Phase 1

Phase 1 was successful as evidenced by the expansion of retail outlets of clients by a whopping 70% within 2 years maintaining an increase in workforce by only 25%.

- Developed a POS software using Android that enhanced the efficiency of billing greatly in retail outlets.
- Enhanced the inventory management solutions which enabled businesses to maintain lean inventory and reduce the working capital of the businesses.
- Developed scalable accounting solutions which drastically reduced the manual labour and manual
- errors faced The primary features include Debit Card/Credit Card reconciliation, UPI transaction reconciliation, Bank reconciliation, and GSTR 2A reconciliation (Purchase Invoice reconciliation). E-Invoicing was automated.
- Automated social media promotions and transaction updates via WhatsApp and email.
- Developed a client application that can be used to track transactions easily.
- Task management system to handle the tasks among the employees of a company.
- Graphical visualisation aids and PDF reports to gain business insights based on sales, revenue generated, etc.
- Gamification Quiz platform to train the employees every day and prizes at the end of every quarter.

Phase 2

After Phase 1, we decided to develop a more scalable product with a core concept of bringing a great level of transparency between manufacturers, sellers and customers through a SAAS-based model, leveraging which each of the stakeholders can reap benefits out of the system.

- Developed a Flutter app for maintaining the product catalogue.
- Part of the development of the backend services using Spring boot, Hibernate which provided REST APIs
 for product creation, order creation, etc.

June 2019–March 2021 | D.E. Shaw & Co, Hyderabad Member Tech - Risk Tech Team

- Developed a portion of the web application which supports the analysis, reporting and other UI
 needsfor the end users to understand the positive or negative impact of macroeconomic events on
 their investments. Enhancements included workflow for analysing monthly and currency exchange
 positionsets with support for comparative analysis among different portfolios.
- It is built using modern web technologies i.e. React, Redux (Using DJS D.E. Shaw Java Script), MongoDB, SQL, and Python (Backend Services).
- Developed REST APIs to consolidate and serve time series analysis of highly contextualised exposure
 data to aid a deeper investigation. I collaborated with the internal cache management team to improve
 the response time of the APIs.Migration of the team's codebase from Python 2 to Python 3 and
 migration of rule analysis framework.

December 2018–May 2019 | D.E. Shaw & Co, Hyderabad Intern

- Worked extensively on the team's web application which aimed at consolidating all RISK needs under one portal. Enhanced to include new workflows using React/Redux.
- Optimised performance up to 1 minute in the load time of the risk web used for Risk Analysis. Improveduser experience by including new chart visualisations namely Scatter chart and TreeMap chart to support data analysis and shortcuts for tech-savvy end users.
- Communicated with internal teams and stakeholders, working to determine solutions for the user experience.

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science and Engineering PSG College of Technology Pursuing Masters in Georgia Institute of Technology

SKILLS

Expertise in:

React

Redux

NextJS

Python

Java

Android

Spring Boot

Hibernate, JPA

Basic Knowledge in:

Deployment in GCP

Flutter